# REGINA GALIEVA

rg-galieva.com github.com/rg-galieva linkedin.com/in/rg-galieva

Experienced full stack engineer, 9+ years in tech. Worked with projects of varying complexity both as an engineer and a team lead. Right now focused on front-end development. Passionate about sophisticated single page apps. In love with Javascript. Have strong skill in responsive layouts. The more challenging features - the better!

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Front-end:** React, MobX, Redux, Typescript, Antd UI **Back-end:** Node, Express, Swagger, Postgres, Mongo

Styles: Sass, Less, PostCss, Css-modules, BEM

**Unit-tests**: Mocha, Jest **Version Control:** Git, Svn

**Dev Tools:** Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Babel, ESLint **Dev Deploy:** Heroku, Amazon S3, Jenkins **Familiar with:** JAVA EE (Spring, Tapestry),

Ruby (RoR), PHP (Wordpress)

Dev Methodology: Agile (Scrum + Kanban)

# **EXPERIENCE**

## [FR8STAR] - Senior Front End Engineer

Load board, freight matching, and bidding marketplace

SF Bay Area, CA May 2017- present

- Feature owner (front-end): request-for-quote flow (entry point for shippers), rate calculator for shippers, load matcher (entry point for carriers), shipper registration, rate calculator widget for partners
- Worked on API-designs, global UI-acrhitecture, reusable responsive components library, style guides, performance optimization, 3rd-party API integration
- Tech stack: React, MobX, google maps API, Node, Swagger

## [ADLUXE] - UI Team Lead

Moscow, RU

Creative technologies, Rich Media and Video Advertising Production

2015-2017

- Led the development of 10+ of company products
- Successfully implemented Agile methodology in a distributed, multi-timezone team
- Moved company website from PHP to React single page app
- Guided team in the development of SPA
- Created an educational tech program for managers and designers (dev fundamentals, is, git, webpack, jenkins)

## [MAIL.RU GROUP] - Front End Developer

Moscow, RU

The leading Russian Internet company with 100M+ users

2013-2015

- Led UI development (code style, code structure, style guides)
- Cross platform development for desktop, mobile, in-game (awesomium) from scratch
- Made 3 global redesigns of the product. Implemented company style guide
- Led UI/UX testina
- Tech stack: Tapestry framework (Java), React, ¡Query.

#### [IFREE] - Web Developer

Saint-Petersburg, RU

Mobile App development & distribution company with \$250M year revenue

2011-2013

- Launched 20+ sites, landings, email newsletters, promo pages (PHP)
- RoR: Developed admin web applications for managing advertisement campaigns using Ruby on Rails
- Java EE: Web applications (front end, back end) using Spring MVC (Maven, JPA, JSP).

# [SIMAI] - Web Developer

Ufa, RU

Digital studio «Simai» lead in the market of information solutions in Ufa

2008-2011

- HTML/CSS/JS coding of web pages, performance optimization, CMS layout templates

#### **EDUCATION**

# **UFA STATE AVIATION TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY**

Ufa, RU

Master's degree in telecommunication systems

2005-2010

#### I-FREE TECHNICAL ACADEMY

Saint-Petersburg, RU

- Was among TOP 20% of chosen to participate in the Academy

2013

- Took the 1st place among 10 projects.

## **GRAPHIC DESIGN BOOTCAMP**

Moscow, RU

10 weeks course: graphic design in web. Effective designs principles, theory and practice

2015